Jurgen Alfaro

Technical Support Engineer | Software Engineer

- 🤨 20302 Grecia, Costa Rica
- ≥ dev.jurgen.alfaro@gmail.com
- (+506) 6111-8011

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jurgen-alfaro-morera-ba3084185/



Profile

Hi! I am a professional Customer Service Representative with over 8 years experience in handling multinational clients. My unique professional experience stems from years of providing excellent customer support, creative problem solving, and building customer loyalty. However, I am now more focused on trying to turn around my career path and start creating and developing amazing apps and services by putting into work my programming skills.

Professional Experience

Technical Support Engineer (L2)

Dell Technologies 🖪

2019/09 – present Heredia, Costa Rica

- Take ownership of technically complex customer reported issues from the web, phone, chat, and email sources to work closely with the customer until it is resolved.
- Analyze, determine, and propose the best course of action for specific customer issues to guide the reported problem into resolution.
- Document relevant information and ensure that the customer is communicated in a timely manner regarding the overall progress of their issue.
- Provide high-level customer service and ensure customers are treated with highest degree of respect.

Technical Support Advisor

Concentrix 🗹

- Assisted with phone and chat channels coverage to ensure uninterrupted customer service throughout the different service lines.
- Advised customers about product-specific features and explained pros and cons of product functionalities.
- Helped customers troubleshoot their devices to isolate hardware or software related issues.
- Scheduled different work orders and on-site appointments for the customers to visit or send their devices for reparation or replacement.

2014/08 – 2019/09 San Jose, Costa Rica

Jurgen Alfaro 1/3

Cameraman

Canal Super 5 🛮

2011/05 – 2014/08 Grecia, Costa Rica

- Organized different workstations to set up audio and video devices.
- Collaborated with the sales, media, and management departments to plan deployment and desired streamline process.
- Recorded and streamed different activities through cable television (news, basketball, political activities, soccer)

Skills

Javascript	• • • • •	HTML	• • • •
CSS	• • • • •	React	• • • • •
NodeJS	• • • • •	SQL	• • • • •

Languages

Spanish

This is my native language.

English

Intermediate English I @ INA - December, 2013

Portuguese

Portuguese Advanced Conversation and Composition @ UTN - July, 2017

Education

Universidad Técnica Nacional

Bachelor in Software Engineering

Currently coursing through the required university modules to obtain the bachelor's degree in Software Engineering.

2018/08 – present

Alajuela, Costa Rica

Universidad Técnica Nacional

Diploma in Software Engineering

Obtained university diploma in Software Engineering for completing the first seven modules in the 'Study Plan'.

2012/01 – 2018/08 Alajuela, Costa Rica

Certificates

Associate - Information Storage and Management Version 4.0 ☑

This badge recognizes the achievement of Dell Technologies Proven Professional Associate - Information Storage and Management Version 4.0 certification. Earners of this badge will have knowledge on data center infrastructure including but not limited to storage and business continuity including software-defined systems and environments for big data, IoT, and mobile technologies.

Specialist - Platform Engineer, XtremIO Version 2.0 ☑

This badge recognizes the achievement of the Dell Technologies Proven Professional Specialist - Platform Engineer, XtremIO Version 2.0 certification. Earners of this badge demonstrated knowledge and practical skills of installing, maintaining, upgrading and expanding XtremIO clusters. Earners of this badge install, configure, validate configurations and replace components in non-disruptive manner.

Jurgen Alfaro 2 / 3

Web interface development

Universidad Cenfotec

Module 1 - HTML & CSS,

Web interface development applying basic layout technics and UI styles.

2021/02 – 2021/05 San Jose, Costa Rica

Projects

ASADA La Lucha, La Tigra de San Carlos

TCU (Trabajo Comunal Universitario)

This project is still under development and was requested by the ASADA La Lucha in La Tigra de San Carlos. Some of the project requirements are:

- Design and develop the ASADA's website by integrating general information (mission, vision, history, contacts, schedules, members of 'Junta Directiva' and their respective charge and validity period)
- The website must include legal forms and have to be available for download ('Solicitud de Servicio Nuevo', 'Disponibilidad de Agua', 'Suspensión Definitiva del Servicio', 'Formulario de Afiliación', etc...)
- Develop a virtual suggestions inbox where people can leave their comments, suggestions, or concerns for a member of the ASADA to review them.
- Include a posts section where the ASADA personnel can upload and publish different ASADA-related topics, like news, financial statements, annual budget, work plan of the Junta Directiva.
- And many other requirements...

alfaro.github.io/buildonauts_cenfotec/

- This project is being built by using React, Tailwind CSS and DaisyUI components as the front-end technologies, and is using NodeJS, Express and MySQL as back-end technologies.
- See the project's repository here: https://github.com/jurgen-alfaro/la-lucha

Buildonauts Cenfotec

2021/02 - 2021/05

This is the first module's final project required by Universidad Cenfotec

This is a project from Universidad Cenfotec. Clone the following website using
Bootstrap: https://buildonauts.com/en

The project was built mainly using HTML, SCSS and Bootstrap framework.

See the deployed website here: https://jurgen-

Jurgen Alfaro 3 / 3

2022/01 – present